RG 004:041, East Haddam Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
East Haddam Probate Court records
1826-2009
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (East Haddam District)
36.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1832-1945; Probate files, 1905-1981; Wills, 1826-2009, bulk 1920-2009.
RG004_041
2011-112, 2012-019, and 2012-036
Historical Note
East Haddam, Middlesex County, Town established in May 1734, Parent Town: Haddam
The East Haddam Probate District was constituted October 1741, from the Hartford Probate District. The East Haddam Probate District merged with the East Hampton, Marlborough, and Portland Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #14 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Haddam, East Hampton, Marlborough and Portland.
Town of East Haddam, Probate District chronology:
May 1734 - October 1741, Hartford District
May 1830 - June 1831, Chatham (i.e. East Hampton) District (covered small section of town)
October 1741 - January 4, 2011, East Haddam District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #14 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-14, 1832-1945. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 14. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1905-1981. East Haddam District probate files dated 1721 to May 28, 1832 are filed with the Colchester District probate files. Prior to the creation of the Colchester District in 1832, the East Haddam District held its probate court in Colchester. The files remained in that town and were kept with the files of the new Colchester District. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Wills, 1826-2009, bulk 1920-2009.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 14.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically.
Each box of wills is arranged alphabetically within the box.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2012-019 and wills in accession 2012-036.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Haddam
Places:
East Haddam (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1981 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
Accession 2011-112, Record books, 1832-1945; Accession 2012-019, Probate files, 1905-1981; and Accession 2012-036, Wills, 1826-2009, bulk 1920-2009, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-5, 8, 10-12, 1832-1922, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in Accession 2011-112 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on February 25, 2011.
The probate files in Accession 2012-019 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 31, 2012.
The wills in Accession 2012-036 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 8, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1832-1945; 7.5 cubic feet (14 volumes); 2011-112
  - Records, 1832-1845 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1832-1843 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1843-1855 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1855-1866 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1866-1879 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1879-1893 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1884-1892 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1882-1918 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1891-1905 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1892-1902 (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1901-1909 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1909-1914 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1914-1922 (Volume 12)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1917-1929 (Volume 13)
  - Bonds, 1918-1945 (Volume 14)
- Probate files, 1905-1981; 25 cubic feet; 2012-019
  - A - Ba (Box 1)
  - Be - Bo (Box 2)
  - Br Bu (Box 3)
  - C - Cone, F. (Box 4)
  - Cone, H. - Dav (Box 5)
  - Day - Dz (Box 6)
  - E - F (Box 7)
  - G (Box 8)
  - Ha - He (Box 9)
  - Hi - J (Box 10)
  - K (Box 11)
  - L (Box 12)
  - Ma - Morg (Box 13)
  - Morr - Pag (Box 14)
  - Pal - Pl (Box 15)
  - Po - Rathbun, F. (Box 16)
  - Rathbun, N. - Ray, Frederick (Box 17)
  - Ray, Frederick - Rostad, M. (Box 18)
  - Rostad, P. - Se (Box 19)
  - Sh - Sm (Box 20)
  - Sn - Sy (Box 21)
  - T - U (Box 22)
  - V - We (Box 23)
  - Wh - Will (Box 24)
  - Wilo - Z (Box 25)
- Wills, 1826-2009, bulk 1920-2009; 4 cubic feet; 2012-036
  - Wills (Box 1-4)